<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Enroute Kanchi</string>
    <string name="Mutt">Sri Kanchi Kamakoti Peetham</string>
    <string name="Temples">Temples</string>
    <string name="Hotels_Lodges">Hotels/Lodges</string>
    <string name="Hotels">Hotels</string>
    <string name="templelist">Temples in Kanchipuram</string>
    <string name="Hotel">Hotels and lodges in Kanchipuram</string>
    <string name="ho1">AKG Lodge</string>
    <string name="Commute">Commute</string>
    <string name="Commute1">Commute (To Kanchipuram)</string>
    <string name="Attractions">Attractions Nearby</string>
    <string name="Attraction">Attractions</string>
    <string name="info">App info</string>
    <string name="appWel">Welcome to Enroute Kanchi</string>
    <string name="Bug">Report a Bug</string>
    <string name="ver">Version: 1.0</string>
    <string name="q">What would you like to know about in Kanchipuram?</string>
    <string name="cap">The one application for all temple information, in Kanchipuram.</string>
    <string name="feed">Your feedback matters the most to us.</string>
    <string name="placeholder">Type something....</string>
    <string name="submit">Submit</string>
    <string name="sign">Designed and developed by SriVardhan and Team.\n\t\t\t\All Copyrights Reserved.</string>
    <string name="KamakshiAmmanTemple">Kamakshi Amman Temple</string>
    <string name="EkambareswararTemple">Ekambareswarar Temple</string>
    <string name="ChitraguptaTemple">Chitragupta Swami Temple</string>
    <string name="KailasanatharTemple">Kailasanathar Temple</string>
    <string name="VaradarajaPerumalTemple">Varadaraja Perumal Temple</string>
    <string name="KumarakottamTemple">Kumarakottam Temple</string>
    <string name="KachabeswararTemple">Kachabeswarar Temple</string>
    <string name="UlagalanthaPerumalTemple">Ulagalandha Perumal Temple</string>
    <string name="Welcome">Welcome to Kanchipuram</string>
    <string name="city">The city of Thousand Temples</string>
    <string name="h1">AKG Lodge</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map__kailasanath">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map__kamakshi">Map</string>
    <string name="desc1">Ekambareswarar Temple(Ekambaranathar Temple) is a Hindu temple dedicated to the deity Shiva, located in the town of Kanchipuram in Tamil Nadu, India and is one of the most widely visited temples in India. This temple is also significant for devotees who opt for Saivism.The idol in this temple refers to <b>Prithvi Lingam</b>\n\nThe temple covers 25 acres, and is one of the largest of its kind in India. The temple complex also consists of Four Gopurams, out of which the one lies in the south is the taller one, consisting of 11 stories and 192ft tall.\n\nThe temple also has six daily rituals, which are performed everyday, starting from 5:30 A.M to 10 P.M. \n\nThe present architecture of the temple was built during Chola dynasty in the 9th century. The temple is now maintained and administered by the Hindu Religious and Charitable Endowments Departments.\n\n Another important thing to know about in this temple is <b>The Mango Tree</b>. It has a great history. Once Parvathi, the consort of Shiva was cursed to become dark like Kali. She wanted to expatiate herself from the sin by doing penance under the temples ancient Mango tree near Vegavathi river. In order to test her devotion Shiva sent fire on her. Goddess Parvati prayed to her brother, Vishnu, for help. In order to save her, he took the Moon from Shivas head and showed the rays which then cooled down the tree as well as Parvati. Shiva again sent the river Ganga (Ganges) to disrupt Parvatis penance. Parvati prayed to Ganga and convinced her that both of them were sisters and so should not harm her. Subsequently, Ganga did not disturb her penance and Parvati made a Shiva Linga out of sand to get united with Shiva. The God here came to be known as Ekambareswarar or "Lord of Mango Tree". \n\n<b>Deity\t</b>:\tSri Ekambareswarar(Lord Shiva)\n\n<b>Opening Times</b>:06:00 A.M to 08:00P.M\n(Closed from 1:00 to 4:00 P.M)</string>
    <string name="map">Take me there</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map__ekam">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map__ulagalanthar">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map__kottam">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map__chitragupta">Map</string>
    <string name="desc2"><b>Kanchi Kamakoti Peetam</b>, is founded by Jagadhguru Sri Adi Shankaracharya, one of the prominent guru\'s of those times. The Peetham along with the other ones across India, has also been an important source for <b>Palm Leaf Manuscripts</b>\n\nThis Peetham is now being led by <b>Vijayendra Saraswathi Swamigal</b></string>
    <string name="desc3"><b>Kamakshi Amman Temple</b>, one of the most prominent Hindu Temples, in India ,is dedicated to Goddess <b>Kamakshi</b>, the ultimate form of Goddess Lalitha Maha Tripura Sundari(Parvathi)devi. The Meenakshi Temple in Madhurai, the Akhilandeswari Temple in Thiruvanaikaval, near Tiruchirapalli and this temple are the important centers of worship of Goddess. The Temple was most probably built by <b>Pallava Kings</b>, whose capital was Kanchipuram in those days.</string>
    <string name="open"><b>Opening Times</b>:12:00 A.M to 12:00P.M</string>
    <string name="open2">\n\n<b>Deity:</b> Kamakshi Amma\n<b>Opening Times</b>:06:00 A.M to 08:00P.M\n(Closed from 1:00 to 4:00 P.M)</string>
    <string name="open10">\n\n<b>Deity:</b> Lord Vishnu\n<b>Opening Times</b>:06:00 A.M to 08:00P.M\n(Closed from 1:00 to 4:00 P.M)</string>
    <string name="open3">\n<b>Deity:</b> Lord Shiva\n<b>Opening Times</b>:06:00 A.M to 08:00P.M\n(Closed from 1:00 to 4:00 P.M)</string>
    <string name="desc4">Kailasanathar temple, is located in Kanchipuram, Tamil Nadu. It is a Hindu Temple, but constructed in Tamil Architecture. It is dedicated to <b>Lord Shiva</b>. The temple is known for it\'s architecture, but unfortunately, most of the temple has been destroyed because of some attacks at that time. The temple was built at the time of <b>Rajasimha</b>,the ruler of Pallava Dynasty.\n\n The temple covers two acres, and has four rituals at various times from 6:00 A.M to 8:30 P.M. Bramhotsavam is the most prominent festival, that is being celebrated her every year.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map__mutt">Map</string>
    <string name="desc5"><b>Varadharaja Perumal Temple</b>, also known as Hasthagiri or Attiyuran is a Hindu Temple,dedicated to <b>Lord Vishnu</b> located in the holy city of Kanchipuram. It is located in the suburb of Kanchipuram known as Vishnu Kanchi, which is a hometown for many Vishnu Temples. This is one of the most sacred places for Vaishnavites. The famous pat of this temple is <b>Golden Lizard and Silver Lizard</b>.\nThe temple is famous for it\'s <b>Huge Umbrella</b> during Festive occasions.</string>
    <string name="open4"><b>Deity</b>:Varadaraja Perumal<b>(Lord Vishnu)</b>\n<b>Opening Times:</b>06:00 A.M to 08:00P.M\n(Closed from 1:00 to 4:00 P.M)</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map__varadaraja">Map</string>
    <string name="desc6">Ulagalantha Perumal temple is dedicated to <b>Lord Vishnu</b>,located in Kanchipuram, Tamil Nadu. This temple was constructed in the Dravidian style of Architecture. Goddess Lakshmi, here, is worshipped as <b>Amudavalli</b>. This is said to be constructed by Pallavas.\n\n The following 6 temple rituals are performed everyday.\n<b>Ushatkalam</b> 7 A.M\n<b>Kalasanthi</b> 8 A.M\n<b>Uchikalam</b> 12 P.M\n<b>Sayarakshai</b> 6 P.M\n<b>Irandamkalam</b> 7 P.M\n<b>Ardhan Jamam</b> 10 P.M\n\nThis Temple is classified as <b>Divyadesam</b>, one of the 108 Vishnu Temples.</string>
    <string name="open5"><b>Deity</b>:Ulagalantha Perumal<b>(Vishnu)</b> and Amudhavalli<b>(Lakshmi)</b>\n<b>Opening Times:</b>06:00 A.M to 08:00P.M\n(Closed from 1:00 to 4:00 P.M)</string>
    <string name="desc7">Kumara Kottam Temple is a Hindu Temple in Kanchipuram, India. <b>Dedicated to Lord Subramanyam</b>, the son of Lord Shiva and Parvathi.\n This temple is famous for the <b>Kandha Shashti</b> festival. It is celebrated by lighting a large no.of lamps</string>
    <string name="open6">\n<b>Deity</b>:Lord Murugan <b>(Subramanya Swami)</b>\n<b>Opening Times</b>:06:00 A.M to 08:00 P.M(Closed between 1:00 to 4:00 P.M)</string>
    <string name="desc8">Chitragupta Temple is a Hindu Temple, located in Kanchipuram, Tamil Nadu. It is considered to be one of the rare temples of the Hindu deity,<b>Chitragupta</b>, who is considered as the assistant of Yama, the Hindu god of Death. It is believed that Lord Chitragupta is emerged from a painting, and has been set as accountant of good and bad deeds of human beings by Brahma. The Temple was built during 9th century.\nThe major festival that is celebrated in this temple is <b>Chitra Pournami</b> during April.</string>
    <string name="open7">\n<b>Deity</b>:Chitragupta Swami\n<b>Opening Times</b>:05:00 A.M to 11:00 P.M (Closed between 12:00 P.M and 05:00 P.M)</string>
    <string name="desc9">Kachabeswarar Temple is a Hindu Temple located in Thirukachur, a village in Kanchipuram, Tamil Nadu. This temple is dedicated to <b>Lord Shiva</b>, and is worshipped as Kachabeswarar.\nThis temple has four rituals at various times, from 6:00 A.M to 8:30 P.M and four festivals in its calendar. <b>Bramhotsavam festival</b> is the most prominent festival for this temple.\n\nThe temple covers two acres of land. The temple has daily rituals at various times from 6:00 A.M to 8:30 P.M. <b>Bramhotsavam</b> festival is celebrated grandly here.\n\n It is believed that the whole temple has been built by Cholas. Now the temple is administered by the Hindu Religious and Charitable Endowments Depratment of Government of TamilNadu.\n\n As per Hindu Legend, Vishnu is in the form of Tortoise(called KARKADA)worshiped Shiva to attain ambrosia at this place.</string>
    <string name="open8"><b>Deity</b>:Kachabeswarar<b>(Lord Shiva)</b>\n<b>Opening Times</b>:06:00 A.M to 09:00 P.M</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map__kacha">Map</string>
    <string name="commute">You can reach Kanchipuram by the following means of Transport</string>
    <string name="commute_desc">Kanchipuram, the temple city is well connected with all the important and prominent cities of TamilNadu,Karnataka and Andhra Pradesh by all means of Transport(i.e, By road, By Air and By Rail).</string>
    <string name="spp">Para goes here....</string>
    <string name="kpm"><i><u>Kanchipuram</u></i></string>
    <string name="his">History of Kanchi</string>
    <string name="chn"><u>From Chennai</u>:</string>
    <string name="chennaiBus">Frequent no.of buses are available to Kanchipuram from Koyambedu Bus stand, also called as CMBT. You can reach CMBT from Chennai Railway station by bus or by metro. Bus stand is vey near to CMBT Metro.</string>
    <string name="chennaiRail">Local trains(MEMU/DEMU) are available to Kanchipuram(Chennai Beach to Tirumalpur via Tambaram, Chengalpattu) everyday,at different times from Park Station, which is nearby Chennai Central Railway station.</string>
    <string name="tpy"><u>From Tirupati</u>:</string>
    <string name="tirupatiBus">Buses are frequently available to Kanchipuram from Tirupati Bus stand(APSRTC, TSRTC and a few private travel buses).\n A few are available from Tirumala too.</string>
    <string name="tirupatiRail">Very few trains are available to Kanchipuram from Tirupati Railway Station\n1 Passenger train: Tirupati Puducherry Passenger\nspl trains(only on a few week days).</string>
    <string name="bng"><u>From Bangalore</u>:</string>
    <string name="bangaloreBus">Buses are frequently available to Kanchipuram from major bus stops at Bangalore(Mostly private buses and a few RTC Buses).</string>
    <string name="bangaloreRail">There are no direct trains running between Bangalore and Kanchipuram. But trains are available up to Arakkonam, from Bangalore. And later, you can grab a bus or MEMU from Arakkonam to reach Kanchipuram.</string>
    <string name="attr_desc">These are the places that you can visit from Kanchipuram.</string>
    <string name="att1">Mahabalipuram</string>
    <string name="att2">Sriperumbudur</string>
    <string name="att3">Pondicherry</string>
    <string name="att4">Tiruttani</string>
    <string name="att5">Vedanthangal Bird Sanctuary</string>
    <string name="att6">Thanjavur</string>
    <string name="att7">Madhurai</string>
    <string name="att8">Thirumannancheri</string>
    <string name="att9">Sripuram</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_att9">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_att8">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_att7">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_att6">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_att5">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_att4">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_att3">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_att2">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_att1">Map</string>
    <string name="sripuram_desc">Golden Temple Vellore complex inside the Sripuram spiritual park is situated at the foot of a small range of green hills at Thirumalaikodi (or simply Malaikodi) Vellore in Tamil Nadu, India. It is 120 km from Tirupati, 145 km from Chennai, 160 km from Puducherry and 200 km from Bengaluru. The Maha Kumbhabhishekam or consecration of the temple and its chief deity, Sri Lakshmi Narayani or Maha Lakshmi, the goddess of wealth, was held on 24 August 2007, and devotees from all religions and backgrounds are welcome to visit. This temple is gilded with 1,500 kg of pure gold,[citation needed] double the 750 kg gilding of the dome of the Golden Temple at Amritsar.</string>
    <string name="thirumanancheri_desc">Thirumanancheri (Thiru Manam Cheri) is a village located near Cauvery River in Nagapattinam district. The village name comes from the god Shiva. Thirumanam mean marriage; cheri denotes a village or hamlet. Shiva married Parvathi at this place so the village is called marriage (Thirumanancheri).Sri Kalyanasundareswarar Temple is a popular visiting place for Hindus.[1] It is one of the shrines of the 275 Paadal Petra Sthalams   Shiva Sthalams glorified in the early medieval Tevaram poems by Tamil Saivite Nayanars Tirugnanasambandar and Tirunavukkarasar.[2] Udhvaganathar Temple is another name for this temple. Edirkolpadi Temple is another popular temple located nearby in the same town. Shiva as the bridegroom is said to have been received at Ethirkolpaadi by His father in law, Bharata Muni.</string>
    <string name="temp_sripuram">Golden Temple:</string>
    <string name="temp_tirumanancheri">Tirumanancheri Temple</string>
    <string name="temp_madhurai">Meenakshi Amma Temple</string>
    <string name="desc_meenakshitemp">Madurai Meenakshi temple was built by King Kulasekara Pandya (1190 1216 CE). He built the main Portions of the three storeyed gopura at the entrance of Sundareswarar Shrine and the central portion of the Goddess Meenakshi Shrine are some of the earliest surviving parts of the temple. The traditional texts call him a poet saint king, additionally credit him with a poem called Ambikai Malai, as well as shrines (koil) each for Natarajar and Surya near the main temple, Ayyanar in the east, Vinayagar in the south, Kariamalperumal in the west and Kali in the north. He also built a Mahamandapam. Kulasekara Pandya was also a poet and he composed a poem on Meenakshi named Ambikai Malai. Maravarman Sundara Pandyan I built a gopura in 1231, then called Avanivendaraman, later rebuilt, expanded and named as Sundara Pandya Thirukkopuram. Chitra gopuram (W), also known as Muttalakkum Vayil, was built by Maravarman Sundara Pandyan II (1238 1251). This gopuram is named after the frescoes and reliefs that depict secular and religious themes of Hindu culture. Maravarman Sundara Pandyan II also added a pillared corridor to the Sundareswara shrine and the Sundara Pandyan Mandapam. It was rebuilt after the 14th century damage, its granite structure was renovated by Kumara Krishnappar after 1595. Though the temple has historic roots, most of the present campus structure was rebuilt after the 14th century CE, further repaired, renovated and expanded in the 17th century by Tirumala Nayaka. In the early 14th century, the armies of Delhi Sultanate led by Muslim Commander Malik Kafur plundered the temple, looted it of its valuables and destroyed the Madurai temple town along with many other temple towns of South India. The contemporary temple is the result of rebuilding efforts started by the Vijayanagara Empire rulers who rebuilt the core and reopened the temple. In the 16th century, the temple complex was further expanded and fortified by the Nayak ruler Vishwanatha Nayakar and later others. The restored complex now houses 14 gopurams (gateway towers), ranging from 45–50m in height, with the southern gopura tallest at 51.9 metres (170 ft). The complex has numerous sculpted pillared halls such as Ayirakkal (1,000 pillar hall), Kilikoondu mandapam, Golu mandapam and Pudu mandapam. Its shrines are dedicated to Hindu deities and Shaivism scholars, with the vimanas above the garbhagrihas (sanctums) of Meenakshi and Sundaresvara gilded with gold. The temple is a major pilgrimage destination within the Shaivism tradition, dedicated to Meenakshi Devi and Shiva. However, the temple includes Vishnu in many narratives, sculptures and rituals as he is considered to be Meenakshi\'s brother. This has made this temple and Madurai as the Southern Mathura, one included in Vaishnava texts. The Meenakshi temple also includes Lakshmi, flute playing Krishna, Rukmini, Brahma, Saraswati, other Vedic and Puranic deities, as well as artwork showing narratives from major Hindu texts. The large temple complex is the most prominent landmark in Madurai and attracts tens of thousands visitors a day. The temple attracts over a million pilgrims and visitors during the annual 10 day Meenakshi Tirukalyanam festival, celebrated with much festivities and a ratha (chariot) procession during the Tamil month of Chittirai (overlaps with April–May in Georgian calendar, Chaitra in North India). The Temple has been adjudged best ‘Swachh Iconic Place’ in India as on October 1, 2017 under Prime Minister of India Narendra Modi\'s Flagship Swachh Bharat Abhiyan.</string>
    <string name="brihadeswaratemple_desc">Brihadishvara Temple, also called Rajarajesvaram or Peruvudaiyār Kōvil, is a Hindu temple dedicated to Shiva located in South bank of Kaveri river in Thanjavur, Tamil Nadu, India. It is one of the largest South Indian temples and an exemplary example of a fully realized Dravidian architecture. It is called as Dhakshina Meru (Meru of south). Built by Tamil king Raja Raja Chola I between 1003 and 1010 AD, the temple is a part of the UNESCO World Heritage Site known as the Great Living Chola Temples, along with the Chola dynasty era Gangaikonda Cholapuram temple and Airavatesvara temple that are about 70 kilometres (43 mi) and 40 kilometres (25 mi) to its northeast respectively. The original monuments of this 11th century temple were built around a moat. It included gopura, the main temple, its massive tower, inscriptions, frescoes and sculptures predominantly related to Shaivism, but also of Vaishnavism and Shaktism traditions of Hinduism. The temple was damaged in its history and some artwork is now missing. Additional mandapam and monuments were added in centuries that followed. The temple now stands amidst fortified walls that were added after the 16th century. Built out of granite, the vimana tower above the sanctum is one of the tallest in South India. It was, in all likelihood, one of the tallest structures in the world at the time of its construction.[citation needed] The temple has a massive colonnaded prakara (corridor) and one of the largest Shiva lingas in India. It is also famed for the quality of its sculpture, as well as being the location that commissioned the brass Nataraja – Shiva as the lord of dance, in 11th century. The complex includes shrines for Nandi, Parvati, Kartikeya, Ganesha, Sabhapati, Dakshinamurti, Chandeshvara, Varahi and others. The temple is one of the most visited tourist attractions in Tamil Nadu.</string>
    <string name="Temp_brihadeshwara">Brihadeshwara Temple:</string>
    <string name="Sanctuary">Vedanthangal Bird Sanctuary is a 30 hectare (74 acre) protected area located in the Chengalpattu District and Madurantakam taluk of the state of Tamil Nadu, India. The sanctuary is about 75 kilometres (47 mi) from Chennai on National Highway 45 ([NH45]). Easily reachable from Madurantakam and Chengalpattu. More than 40,000 birds (including 26 rare species), from various parts of the world visit the sanctuary during the migratory season every year. Vedanthangal is home to migratory birds such as pintail, garganey, grey wagtail, blue winged teal, common sandpiper and the like. Vedanthangal is the oldest water bird sanctuary in the country. Vedanthangal in Tamil language means \'hamlet of the hunter\'. This area was a favourite hunting spot of the local landlords in the early 18th century. The region attracted a variety of birds because it was dotted with small lakes that acted as feeding grounds for the birds. Realising its ornithological importance, the British government undertook steps to develop Vedanthangal into a bird sanctuary as early as 1798. This was established in 1858 by the order of the Collector of Chengalpattu. The pathway in Vedanthangal Bird Sanctuary. The best time to visit this sanctuary is from November to March. During this time, birds are seen busy building and maintaining their nests. Villagers near this sanctuary are very concerned about the sanctuary and its winged residents, and they have taken many serious steps to avoid disturbance to the flow of birds.</string>
    <string name="temple_Tiruttani">Murugan Temple:</string>
    <string name="Tiruttanitemp_desc">Thiruthani Murugan temple is a Hindu temple, on the hill of Thiruttani, Tiruvallur district, Tamil Nadu, India, dedicated to Lord Muruga. The hill has 365 steps indicating 365 days of the year. It is one of the Arupadaiveedu, the six holy abodes of Lord Muruga. The other five are Palani Murugan Temple, Swamimalai Murugan Temple, Tirupparangunram Murugan Temple, Pazhamudircholai and Thiruchendur Murugan Temple. Thiruthani is 87 kilometres (54 mi) from Chennai.</string>
    <string name="Temple_pandava">Pandava Dootha Temple</string>
    <string name="plc1">Enter your name</string>
    <string name="feed1">Describe your Issue</string>
    <string name="mail_place">Enter your Email address</string>
    <string name="mahabalipuram">Shore Temple\nPancha Rathas\nDescent of the Ganges\nGroup of Monuments\nVaraha cave Temple\nKrishna\'s Butterball\nThirukadalmallai\nMahabalipuram Beach\nKrishna Mandapam</string>
    <string name="mahabalipuram_desc">Mamallapuram, also known as Mahabalipuram, is a town in Chengalpattu district in the southeastern Indian state of Tamil Nadu, best known for the UNESCO World Heritage Site of 7th  and 8th century Hindu Group of Monuments at Mamallapuram. Mamallapuram was one of two major port cities by the 7th century within the Pallava kingdom. The town was named after Pallava king Narasimhavarman I, who was also known as Mahamalla. Along with economic prosperity, it became the site of a group of royal monuments, many carved out of the living rock. These are dated to the 7th and 8th centuries: rathas (temples in the form of chariots), mandapas (cave sanctuaries), the giant open air rock relief the Descent of the Ganges, and the Shore Temple dedicated to Shiva, Durga, Vishnu, Krishna and others. The contemporary town plan was established by the British Raj in 1827.</string>
    <string name="mbp1">Shore Temple</string>
    <string name="mbp2">Pancha Rathas</string>
    <string name="mbp3">Descent of the Ganges</string>
    <string name="mbp4">Group of Monuments</string>
    <string name="mbp5">Varaha cave Temple</string>
    <string name="mbp6">Krishna\'s Butterball</string>
    <string name="mbp7">Thirukadalmallai</string>
    <string name="mbp8">Mahabalipuram Beach</string>
    <string name="mbp9">Krishna Mandapam</string>
    <string name="srip">Sri Ramanujar Temple\nVallakottai Subhramanya Swami Temple\nRajiv Gandhi Memorial</string>
    <string name="srip1">Sri Ramanujar Temple</string>
    <string name="srip2">Vallakottai Subhramanya Swami Temple</string>
    <string name="srip3">Rajiv Gandhi Memorial</string>
    <string name="srip1_desc">Adi Kesava Temple (also called Ramanujar Temple) is dedicated to Hindu god Vishnu located in Sriperumbudur, Kanchipuram district, in the South Indian state of Tamil Nadu. Constructed in the Dravidian style of architecture, dedicated to Vishnu, who is worshipped as AdiKesava and his consort Lakshmi as ethiraja nadhavalli. The temple is believed to be the birthplace of Ramanuja, the exponent of Vishishtadvaita philosophy. The gold plated shrine in front of the hall of Ramanuja was built by the Maharaja of Mysore. The temple is open from 6:30 a.m. to 12 p.m. and 4 p.m. to 8 p.m and has six daily rituals at various times of the day. Various festivals are celebrated in the temple, with the Chitirai Brahmotsavam, Masi Pooram festival during February   March and Panguni Uthiram festival during March   April being the most prominent. The temple is maintained and administered by the Hindu Religious and Endowment Board of the Government of Tamil Nadu.</string>
    <string name="srip2_desc">Vallakottai Subramaniyaswami temple (or Vallakottai Murugan temple) in Vallakottai, a panchayat town in Kanchipuram district in the South Indian state of Tamil Nadu, is dedicated to the Hindu god Murugan. Constructed in the Dravidian style of architecture, the temple is located in the Sriperumbudur   Singaperumalkoil road. The temple has a gateway leading to a pillared hall and the sanctum. The temple is open from 6:30 am – 12:00 pm and 5   8:30 pm. Five daily rituals and many yearly festivals are held at the temple, of which the Adi Pooram festival being the most prominent. The temple is maintained and administered by the Hindu Religious and Endowment Board of the Government of Tamil Nadu.</string>
    <string name="srip3_desc">The Rajiv Gandhi Memorial is a memorial to Indian prime minister Rajiv Gandhi at the site where he was assassinated at Sriperumbudur, Chennai, Tamil Nadu India. Designed by K T Ravindran, it was built by the Central Public Works Department and was opened up in 2003 by Gandhi\'s widow Sonia Gandhi and former President of India APJ Abdul Kalam.</string>
    <string name="pandavTemp_desc">Lord Vishnu, during his incarnation as shri Krishna , the lord saved the virtuous Pandavas from the cluthes of the evil minded kauravas , strove to make clear the distinction between Dharma and Adharma and proved the ultimate triumph of Dharama over Adharam when he visited Vidura\'s residence Vidhura immersed in Joy and forgetting himself, offered him the peel of a plantain thinking that he was offering only the fruit. To avoid his disappointment, Lord Krishna took it heartly. The Omnipresent Lord allowed himself to be bound by Sahadeva\'s affection. He did many more queer things to show his Sowlabhya, the most remarkable amongst them being his acceptance to take up the role of an emissary of Pandavas and to go to the court of the Kauravas. An efficient emissary should possess two characteristics. First he should convey the message so skillfully as to render it acceptable. Secondly he should complete the mission to the satisfaction of the persons whom he represents. Sri Krisha went to the Kauravas as an emissary of peace but returned to the Pandavas camp agreeing for a battle. A doubt naturally arises as to whether he fulfilled his mission successfully. We get the answer to this question in the chapter dealing with Yudhistra\'s gambling in the game of dice wherein, except him, the other four brothers as well as Draupadi swear to take revenge on Duryodhana and his gang. Thus looking retrospectively, there is no room for doubt about Krishna\'s efficient handling of his mission. He agreed for war just to keep their promises alive and that is why he even accepted to become Parthasarathy, the charioteer of Arjuna. During this mission, the foolish Duryodhana even attempted to kill Him devising a plan to make Him occupy a seat with a carpet spread over a void underneath so that it would tumble down, the moment it was occupied, into an underground room where mighty wrestlers would be ready to crush Him. Duryodhana, not only dragged the emissary into a heated discussion, little realising that his duty was just to deliver the message but also plotted to kill Him against all canons of statemanship. Contrary to their expectations, the Omniscient and the Omnipotent Krishna, assumed Vishwaroopa, in comparison with which the deep pit constructed by them looked in dimension just like a pin hole, and could not be trapped. The pious in that assembly worshiped Him chanting Ashtakshara mantra and the wicked trembled in fear to face His wrath. Even the blind king, Dhrutharashtra, was fourtunate enough, to get eye sight by His grace to have darshan of His glittering form. When Lord Krishna offered him a boon, he desired to become blind as before since he did not want to see the temporal things after perceiving the eternal form of the Lord. This is one of the most important episodes in Krishnavatara. When Janamejaya, the great grand son of Arjuna and sage Hareetha performed severe penance to have a glimpse of that form of Sri Krishna, the Lord gave darshan to them in that mangnificent form and that sacred place is the shrine of \'Padagam\' in Kancheepuram.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_dootha_temp">Map</string>
    <string name="pandavadootha_temple">Pandavadootha Temple</string>
    <string name="history">History of Kanchipuram</string>
    <string name="history_1">\n\nKanchipuram, also known as Kanchi, is a temple city in the Indian state of Tamil Nadu in Tondaimandalam region, 72 km (45 mi) from Chennai, the capital of Tamil Nadu. The city covers an area of 11.605 sq.km (4.481 sq mi) and had a population of 164,265 in 2011. It is the administrative headquarters of Kanchipuram District. Kanchipuram is well-connected by road and rail. Chennai International Airport is the nearest domestic and international airport to the city, which is located at Tirusulam in Kanchipuram district.\n\n\t\tLocated on the banks of the Vegavathy river, Kanchipuram has been ruled by the Pallavas, the Medieval Cholas, the Later Cholas, the Later Pandyas, the Vijayanagara Empire, the Carnatic kingdom, and the British, who called the city Conjeeveram. The historical monuments include the Kailasanathar Temple and the Vaikunta Perumal Temple. Historically, Kanchipuram was a centre of education and was known as the ghatikasthanam, or place of learning. The city was also a religious centre of advanced education for Jainism and Buddhism between the 1st and 5th centuries. \n\n\t\tIn Vaishnavism Hindu theology, Kanchipuram is one of the seven Tirtha (pilgrimage) sites, for spiritual release. The city houses Varadharaja Perumal Temple, Ekambareswarar Temple, Kamakshi Amman Temple, and Kumarakottam Temple which are some of major Hindu temples in the state. Of the 108 holy temples of the Hindu god Vishnu, 15 are located in Kanchipuram. The city is particularly important to Sri Vaishnavism, but is also a holy pilgrimage site in Shaivism. The city is well known for its hand woven silk sarees and most of the city\'s workforce is involved in the weaving industry.</string>
    <string name="Share">Share This App</string>
    <string name="visit">Places to visit:</string>
    <string name="pondi1">Puducherry Beach</string>
    <string name="pondi2">Botanical Garden</string>
    <string name="pondi3">Serenity Beach Sunrise Point</string>
    <string name="Pondi_places">Puducherry Beach \nBotanical Garden \nSerenity Beach Sunrise Point</string>
    <string name="pondi_desc">Pondicherry, officially known as Puducherry, is the capital and the most populous city of the Indian Union Territory of Puducherry, with a population of 657,209 and an area of 492 sq.km. The city is located in the Puducherry district on the southeast coast of India, and is surrounded by the state of Tamil Nadu with which it shares most of its culture and language. Pondicherry city consists of 42 wards. Wards 1–10 are north of the city. Wards 11–19 are in Boulevard Town and remaining wards are southwest of the city centre.</string>
    <string name="mbp1_desc">The Shore Temple (built in 700–728 AD) is so named because it overlooks the shore of the Bay of Bengal. It is located near Chennai in Tamil Nadu. \n\nMarco Polo and the European merchants that came to Asia after him called the site Seven Pagodas. One of these is believed to be the Shore Temple. The temple probably acted as a landmark for navigation of their ships. As it appears like a Pagoda, the name became familiar to the seafarers.</string>
    <string name="mbp2_desc">Pancha Rathas (also known as Five Rathas or Pandava Rathas) is a monument complex at Mahabalipuram, on the Coromandel Coast of the Bay of Bengal, in the Kancheepuram district of the state of Tamil Nadu, India. Pancha Rathas is an example of monolithic Indian rock-cut architecture. The complex was carved during the reign of King Narasimhavarman I (630–668 AD): the idea of realising monolithic buildings, an innovation in Indian architecture, is attributed to this ruler. The complex is under the auspices of the Archaeological Survey of India (ASI) and is part of the UNESCO World Heritage site inscribed by UNESCO as Group of Monuments at Mahabalipuram. \n\nEach of the five monuments in the Pancha Rathas complex resembles a chariot (ratha), and each is carved over a single, long stone or monolith, of granite which slopes in north-south direction with a slight incline. Though sometimes mistakenly referred to as temples, the structures were never consecrated because they were never completed following the death of Narasimhavarman I. The structures are named after the Pancha Pandavas and their common wife Draupadi, of epic Mahabharata fame. In order of their size, they include the Dharmaraja Ratha, Bhima Ratha, Arjuna Ratha, Nakula Sahadeva Ratha, and Draupadi Ratha.</string>
    <string name="mbp3_desc">Descent of the Ganges is a monument at Mamallapuram, on the Coromandel Coast of the Bay of Bengal, in the Chengalpattu district of the state of Tamil Nadu, India. Measuring 96 by 43 feet (29 m × 13 m), it is a giant open-air rock relief carved on two monolithic rock boulders. The legend depicted in the relief is the story of the descent of the sacred river Ganges to earth from the heavens led by Bhagiratha. The waters of the Ganges are believed to possess supernatural powers. The descent of the Ganges and Arjuna\'s Penance are portrayed in stone at the Pallava heritage site. The relief is more of a canvas of Indian rock cut sculpture at its best not seen anywhere in India. It is one of the Group of Monuments at Mamallapuram that were designated as a UNESCO World Heritage Site since 1984. The relief was created to celebrate the victory of Narasimhavarman 1 over Chalukiya king Pulakesin 2 . The place, now known as Mamallapuram, was earlier known by the epithet given to the king Narasimhavarman I (630–668 AD) of the Pallava Dynasty (who ruled from 4th to 9th centuries), as Mamallan, the great wrestler or great warrior. His father was king Mahendravarman I. The architectural creations at Mamallapuram, mostly attributed to Mamalla in the 7th century, adopted stone as the medium for sculpting in situ rock faces, which until then was done with some perishable material like wood or loose stones. It is part of 25 UNESCO World Heritage Cultural Sites in India, and as a protected monument, the Archaeological Survey of India(ASI)</string>
    <string name="mbp4_desc">The Group of Monuments at Mamallapuram is a collection of 7th- and 8th-century CE religious monuments in the coastal resort town of Mamallapuram, Tamil Nadu, India and a UNESCO World Heritage Site. It is on the Coromandel Coast of the Bay of Bengal, about 60 kilometres (37 mi) south of Chennai.</string>
    <string name="mbp5_desc">Varaha Cave Temple (also Adivaraha Cave Temple) is a rock-cut cave temple located at Mamallapuram, on the Coromandel Coast of the Bay of Bengal in Kancheepuram District in Tamil Nadu, India. It is part of the hill top village, which is 4 kilometres (2.5 mi) to the north of the main Mahabalipurm sites of rathas and the Shore Temple. It is an example of Indian rock-cut architecture dating from the late 7th century. The temple is one of the finest testimonial to the ancient Vishwakarma Sthapathis, of rock-cur cave architecture, out of many such caves also called mandapas. Part of the Group of Monuments at Mahabalipuram, the temple is a UNESCO World Heritage Site as inscribed in 1984 under criteria i, ii, iii and iv. The most prominent sculpture in the cave is that of Lord Vishnu in the incarnated form of a Varaha or boar lifting Bhudevi, the mother earth goddess from the sea. Also carved are many mythical figures.</string>
    <string name="mbp6_desc">Krishna\'s Butterball (also known as Vaan Irai Kal and Krishna\'s Gigantic Butterball) is a gigantic granite boulder resting on a short incline in the historical coastal resort town of Mamallapuram in Tamil Nadu state of India.  The Pallava king Narasimhavarman (630–668 CE) also made a failed attempt to move the boulder. The Indian Tamil king Raja Raja Chola (985 and 1014 CE) was inspired by the balance of this massive stone boulder and it led to the creation of never falling mud dolls called Tanjavur Bommai, which having a half-spherical base tends to come back to its original position every time one tries to make it fall. In 1908, then-governor of the city Arthur Havelock made an attempt to use seven elephants to move the boulder from its position due to safety concerns, but with no success. On October 12th 2019, Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi and Chinese President Xi Jinping took a photo in front of Krishna\'s Butterball holding hands during their second informal summit.</string>
    <string name="mbp7_desc">Sthalasayana Perumal Temple (also called Thirukadalmallai) is at Mahabalipuram. Constructed in the Dravidian style of architecture, the temple is glorified in the Divya Prabandha, the early medieval Tamil canon of the Azhwar saints from the 6th–9th centuries AD. It is one of the 108 Divyadesam dedicated to Vishnu, who is worshipped as Sthalasayana Perumal and his consort Lakshmi as Nilamangai Thayar. The temple is believed to have been built by Pallavas, with later contributions from Medieval Cholas, Vijayanagar kings and Madurai Nayaks. References to modern day Mahabalipuram as a busy port is available in the works of Ptolemy from AD 140. There are many references to the place from Sangam Literature from third century AD. The temple is referred in the works of seventh century works of Bhoothath Azhwar and eighth century works of Thirumangai Azhwar. The port city came to prominence during the reign of Pallava kings Mahendravarman I and his son Narasimhavarman I after whom the city is named. The city was a famous port city during the reign of Medieval Cholas from the 9th century. There are inscriptions in the temple indicating grants of 1000 kulis during the 20th year of reign of Ko-Parakesarivarman.</string>
    <string name="mbp8_desc">Some 58 km south of the Chennai, there lies a spectacular beach in Tamilnadu shored by the Bay of Bengal, Mahabalipuram or locally referred as Mamallapuram. From the 8th century Shore Temple on the seashore to rock-cut sculptures and monuments like Monolithic Rathas and Caves, this bewitching tourist attraction in Tamilnadu is a perfect blend of historical significance and nature resplendence. This charming beach is one of the perfect places in India for sunbath (which is the must-do activity here), and thus, lures larger chunk tourists both domestic as well as overseas. Moreover, If you’re into windsurfing and swimming, don’t hesitate to hit the shores of the beach while playing with the moving tides. The charm of this beautiful place doesn’t end here, it also has wildlife experience to proffer to nature lovers or history buffs as there is crocodile bank and snake venom extracting center situated just a few km away from the beach. Furthermore, what catches the tourists eyes more in Mahabalipuram is the special event of Dance Festival which held every year in December or January.</string>
    <string name="mbp9_desc">Mandapa of Krishna or Krishna Mandapam is a monument at Mahabalipuram, on the Coromandel Coast of the Bay of Bengal, in the Kancheepuram district of the state of Tamil Nadu, India. It is part of the Group of Monuments at Mahabalipuram, a UNESCO World Heritage Site inscribed in 1984. It is located on a hillock next to the open rock relief of Descent of the Ganges (Mahabalipuram).  It is constituted by an originally open-air bas-relief dedicated to Lord Krishna, dating to the mid-seventh century, which was later enclosed within a mandapa in the 16th century during the Vijayanagara Empire. Notable carvings inside are sculpted panels that bring out the story of Krishna lifting the Govardhana Hill to protect the cowherds and gopis (milk maids) from heavy rains and floods the most poetic and endearing Indian or Angkor sculpture-based representation of this legend and there are also scenes of Krishna frolicking with the milk maids.</string>
    <string name="pondi1_desc">Pondicherry is among those popular destinations in India which are as versatile as it is beautiful. There are enough wonderful Places to Visit and Things to do in Pondicherry to make your visit to this delightful French Colonial Settlement in India, a truly memorable affair. While the historically enriched locales and sumptuous food of this Union Territory are as much famous, it is the immensely gorgeous and peaceful Beaches in Pondicherry that grab the limelight. The shimmering azure water coupled with immaculate golden sands along its long coastline set Pondicherry Beaches apart from any other beach destination in India.</string>
    <string name="pondi2_desc">The Botanical Garden is located south of the New Bus Stand. The gate leading to the garden is reminiscent of French architecture and it stands out from its immediate surroundings because it is in the middle of the old Tamil town. The Botanical Gardens were laid out in 1826 in the ornate French style, with pruned trees, flower beds and gravel lined paths and fountains. Perrottet was largely responsible for transforming the place into a botanical garden in 1831. The French introduced many exotic plants from all over the world. The gardens also have a musical fountain which is active over the weekends, with two shows in the evening.</string>
    <string name="pondi3_desc">Serenity beach is on the way from Pondicherry to Auroville. The beach is quiet and peaceful during the weekdays, however on weekends one will see a lot of locals there. It’s advisable to visit during the day and one can easily spend 2 – 3 hours, the beach also has few shacks, serving quick bite and sea food. If you are solo travelers a walk on the beach and playing with the waves is the perfect pastime or you can also do a picnic with friends and family. One can come also here to catch the sunrise and sip coconut water or have a hot coffee while the sunsets with a walk on the shore and catch the waves. Around serenity beach there are plenty of restaurants offering variety of cuisine like Italian, French and South Indian.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_sreeman">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_hotels__map">Map</string>
    <string name="yatothkari_temple">Yathothkari Perumal Temple</string>
    <string name="yatothkari_temple_desc">Tiruvekkaa Temple or Yathothkari Perumal Temple (locally called Sonnavannam Seitha Perumal) is a Hindu temple located in Kanchipuram in the South Indian state of Tamil Nadu and dedicated to the Hindu god Vishnu. Constructed in the Dravidian style of architecture, the temple is glorified in the Divya Prabandha, the early medieval Tamil canon of the Azhwar saints from the 6th–9th centuries AD. It is one of the 108 Divyadesam dedicated to Vishnu, who is worshipped as Yathothkari Perumal and his consort Lakshmi as Komalavalli. \nThe temple is considered one of three oldest Vishnu temples in Kanchipuram, the other two being Ulagalantha Perumal Temple and Pandava Thoothar Perumal Temple. The temple is believed to have been built by the Pallavas of the late 8th century AD, with later contributions from Medieval Cholas and Vijayanagar kings. The temple has three inscriptions on its walls, two dating from the period of Kulothunga Chola I (1070–1120 CE) and one to that of Rajadhiraja Chola (1018-54 CE). A granite wall surrounds the temple, enclosing all the shrines. There is a three tiered rajagopuram, the temples gateway tower, in the temple.\nYathothkari Perumal is believed to have appeared for Saraswati and Thirumalisai Alvar. Six daily rituals and three yearly festivals are held at the temple. The temple houses a rare image of Ranganatha recumbent on his left hand unlike other temples where he is recumbent on his right. The temple is maintained and administered by the Hindu Religious and Endowment Board of the Government of Tamil Nadu.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_yatothkari__map">Map</string>
    <string name="astabujakaram">Astabujakaram Temple</string>
    <string name="astabujakaram_desc">Ashtabujakaram or Ashtabuja Perumal Temple located in Kanchipuram in the South Indian state of Tamil Nadu, is dedicated to the Hindu god Vishnu. Constructed in the Dravidian style of architecture, the temple is glorified in the Divya Prabandha, the early medieval Tamil canon of the Azhwar saints from the 6th–9th centuries AD. It is one of the 108 Divyadesam dedicated to Vishnu, who is worshipped as Ashta Bhuja Perumal and his consort Lakshmi as Alamelumangai.\nThe temple is believed to have been built by the Pallavas of the late 8th century AD, with later contributions from Medieval Cholas and Vijayanagar kings. The temple has three inscriptions on its walls, two dating from the period of Kulothunga Chola I (1070–1120 CE) and one to that of Rajendra Chola (1018-54 CE). A granite wall surrounds the temple, enclosing all the shrines and two bodies of water. There is a four tiered rajagopuram, the temples gateway tower, in the temple.\nSix daily rituals and three yearly festivals are held at the temple. The temple is maintained and administered by the Hindu Religious and Endowment Board of the Government of Tamil Nadu.</string>
    <string name="nilthingal_thundam">Nilthingalthundam perumal Temple</string>
    <string name="nilthingal_thundam_desc">Nilthingal Thundam Perumal temple (also called Chandrasoodeswarar Perumal temple) is a Hindu temple dedicated to Vishnu, located in Kanchipuram in the state of Tamil Nadu, India.The temple is located in a shrine in Ekambareswarar Temple, the largest temple in the town of Kanchipuram, located in the northern part of the town. The temple gopuram (gateway tower) is 59m tall, which is one of the tallest gopurams in India.The temple is glorified in the Divya Prabandha, the early medieval Tamil canon ofthe Azhwar saints from the 6th–9th centuries AD.It is one of the 108 Divyadesam dedicated to Vishnu, who is worshiped as Nilathingal Thunda Perumal and his consort Lakshmi as Nilathingal Thunda Nayagi.\nSix daily rituals and two major yearly festivals are held at the temple, of which the Vaikunta Ekadasi festival, celebrated during the Tamil month of Margazhi (December - January), is the most prominent.\nThe temple is maintained and administered by the Hindu Religious and Endowment Board of the Government of Tamil Nadu. Unlike other Vaishnavite temples where a Vaishnavite priest officiates, the temples has a Saiva priest as it in inside a Shiva temple.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_astabujakaram__map">Map</string>
    <string name="title_activity_nilthingal__map">Map</string>
    <string name="att10">Mani Mandapam</string>
    <string name="att10_desc">A great temple for <b>Pujyasri Chandrasekharendra Saraswathi Swamiji</b>, 68th Shankaracharya of Sri Kanchi Kamakoti Peetam, built at Orikkai, a suburb of Kanchipuram about 5 kilometres from Kanchipuram. The temple is unique in many ways that embodies the age old tradition combined with modern aspirations. The temple falls under the category of suddha variety, meaning entirely built of one material, namely stone. There are other temples built of mixed materials like stone, bricks, wood, metal and mortar, that are called misra vimanas but when built of one material alone, as in the case of the Great Temple of Thanjavur, it comes to be called Shuddha Vimana, generally built by Emperors.\nSecondly, the main temple is about one hundred feet in height, symbolizing the life span of His Holiness who lived amidst us for nearly one hundred years.  All ancient temples were built, reflecting certain basic philosophies and this follows those traditional concepts. The superstructure called the Sikhara is about 56 feet and the height is one and three fourth, the width that is 1: 1.3/4 proportions bears a particular name indicating happiness (Ananda vimana), according to the sthapati.\nThe white granite stones for this temple have come from a village named Pattimalai kuppam about 50 miles from Kanchipuram. The temple consists of two parts, the main vimana with sikhara and second the front mandapa with one hundred pillars\nThe main sikhara is built on a high upapitha and with the traditional with several musings. The sikhara is built in five storeys topped by the stupika also made of stone. The sikhara is beautified with rows of corner kutas, intermediate shalas, and the central Projections (bhadras) provided with windows (jalas) for lighting and ventilation.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_map_att10">Map</string>
</resources>